Willow Alber-Martin

Boulder, CO · (720) 525-8664 · wial6657@colorado.edu · walbermartin.com

I am a driven undergraduate with extensive experience in instruction and communication. I am proficient at managerial tasks and event planning, with additional skills in lab settings and data science.

Education

Boulder, CO 6/2021 - Present University of Colorado, Boulder, Molecular and Cellular Biology

Bachelor of Arts, May 2022

GPA: 3.4/4.00

New York University, Shanghai, Biology

Shanghai, China 8/2018 - 1/2020

Bachelor of Science, May 2022

GPA: 3.2/4.00

Experience

University of Colorado, Boulder - Learning Assistant Boulder, CO 1/2021 - Present

I teach coseminars, hold office hours, and respond to student concerns in order to facilitate communication between the students and professors in Genetics and Introduction to Cellular Biology.

Mentor Collective - Mentor

Boulder, CO 8/2021 - Present I engage one-on-one with a group of assigned freshmen in order to help them make the transition

to college. I help these freshmen find and use school resources, and I provide feedback to the school so that they can improve new students' experience.

Heart 2 Heart - Child Supervisor

Shanghai, China 8/2019 - 12/2019

I ran fundraisers for families with children in need of heart surgery, and spent time with pre and post-operational children while they were in the hospital.

Restaurateur Club - President

Shanghai, China 1/2021 - 5/2021

I reached out to restaurant owners in Shanghai to plan visits to their businesses for the student body chapter.

YouthRoots - Intern Denver, CO 8/2016 - 12/2017

I created teaching modules for future classes and organized the annual end of year banquet.

Skills: Lab Procedures/Assays:

Conversational fluency in Mandarin

Semi-fluent in Korean

LaTeX, HTML/CSS

Python for data science/scripting

BLS Certified

SDS-PAGE **Restriction Digests**

Enrichment and plaque assays

isolation **PCR**

Select Projects

- Developed a restriction enzyme simulator using python and the Saccharomyces Genome Database for identifying cheap, off-the-shelf restriction enzymes that can be used for DNA fingerprinting.
- Built a low cost incubator for growing cultures.
- Compared DIY gelatin based cellular growth medium to lab grade agar.